Guide to the Shasta Dredging Co. Records, 1911-1922
Department of Special Collections
Shasta Dredging Co. Records,
1911-1922
Special Collections M0204
Shasta Dredging Co.
2 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Restricted access: requires 24 hr. paging period.
Provenance
Purchased from Wendell Hammon, 1971.
Scope and Content
A collection of correspondence, reports, legal papers, business papers, and maps of the Shasta Dredging Co. of Shasta Co., California. Sufficient detail is presented to enable the reader to understand the day to day operations of the company, and some of the major problems it faced.
Container List
- A. Correspondence and Reports.
  - General file: correspondence re potential dredging sites in Shasta County, California; (Igo property, Dry Creek; Russell property; Cottonwood creek- Hiens and Shuffleton Tracts); includes survey reports, estimates of yield and operations costs, and correspondence re decision not to buy the Igo property. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Field Reports: Clear Creek; Cottonwood Creek properties; Dry Creek; Gleason Tract. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Barringer, Daniel M. (owner or substantial creditor) File includes correspondence, legal papers, reports- an overall view of operations: 1916. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1918 - 1922. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dakin property. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Smith, G. V. (General Manager).
    - (a) Correspondence between Smith and J. F. Newsom, President of the Shasta Dredging Co., mostly re Cottonwood properties operations: 1916 - 1917. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1918 - 1922. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - (b) Manager's monthly operations reports. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - (c) Field log- shaft and drill results:
      - Dry Creek, 1916 - 1917.
      - Cottonwood Creek, 1916.
      - Dakins Property, 1916. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Summaries of Dredging. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- B. Legal Papers.
  - Cottonwood Creek properties contracts. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- C. Maps and Blueprints.
  - Summaries of operations, blueprints (33) 1911 - 1920. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous maps, including:
    - Clear Creek; Cottonwood Creek; (lower tract) Diestelhorst Tract; Dry Creek. (Box 3, Folder 2, Folder 3)
  - Cottonwood Creek properties, maps. (19) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - (a) One large clothbacked map of Cottonwood Creek. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lost Channel Mine maps (4). (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Redding, California maps; including map of Dakin properties. (7) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    See also large oversize map at back of box IV.
  - Blueprint maps of dredging progress and scheduled work. (23) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Blueprint positives. (Box 4, Folder 5)